hi coach bre and terce here here's a
video on Bulgarian split
squats so many of you perform and
program uh the Bulgarian split squat
into your routines and it's a great
exercise and most of you probably do it
like this you you or your clients put
your back foot up on a bench like this
come down come up okay there's nothing
wrong with this but I think there's a
better way check out my foot right here
it's uncomfortable it's stretched I can
put my toe up like this but that never
felt right to me
either so I've actually been doing it
this way for about 8 years now I don't
use a
bench I use a barbell in a rack so I put
the bar in the rack that I like it at
I put it at this height for taller
people one lower for shorter people I
will take a thick bar pad and place it
around the
bar now if I just did it like this this
bar Wiggles while you do it you don't
want the bar moving so I take
bands and I go like this
[Music]
okay now this isn't moving anywhere it's
going to stay put so I like to go from a
higher position most people a lower
position because they're not as tall as
me but right now as you can see
my it's this is a rounded pth the crooks
of my ankle here is rounded so it fits
to the Contour of my anatomy so now it's
just so much more comfortable you can
have dumbbells or a barbell sink down
and it just feels so much more natural
there's no pain there um
some pointers in form you want to think
you know most of the weight on the front
leg the back leg is just for some
stability so think you know 85 to 90% of
the load is going to be on the front leg
you want to push through the heel you
can lean forward slightly and that may
help increase glute activation a little
bit but you don't want to let the hips
rise faster than the knee so show you
what that means so if I come down down
to here see I'm leaning forward a little
bit but I don't want my hips to shoot up
first so make sure your hip and knee
rise at the same speed
okay anyway give this method a try I
think you'll like it more than the
standard bench version I know some
equipment manufacturers make single leg
squat stands uh for example SX makes one
and that works great too but here's a
way to do it without one thank you for
watching